Guide to the New-York Historical Society Pictorial Archive 1804-2009 (bulk 1900s-1970s) NYHS-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Exhibitions, 1932-2000; 8.23 Linear feet
  - Steamboat and Railroad Prints; Albert Gallatin, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Prentis Rooms, 1951 May (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - History in Manuscripts; Survivors of a Century: New York City Newspapers, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Recent Accessions; 19th Century Children's Books; Early New York Gallery, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Early American Toys (Prentis Murphy and Hortense Carney collections), 1951 December (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Country Houses on Manhattan Built Before 1860, 1952 January (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 150th Anniversary of U.S. Military Academy (West Point), 1952 March (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sculptured Portraits of Distinguished Citizens by Malvina Hoffman, 1952 April (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Hats in the Ring, 1952 June (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Votes for Women, 1952 October (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Includes three photographs of Eleanor Roosevelt at the exhibition and speaking at the podium.
  - Golden Anniversary of Greater New York, 1953 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Circus Time, 1953 April (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Some of the photographs in this folder appear to be misfiled as they likely relate to a 1968 circus poster exhibition instead. On the other hand, the 1968 exhibition folder includes photographs from this 1953 exhibition. See the folder "Circus Posters from the Days of the Big Top" below at March 1968.
  - The Healing Art of Old New York, 1953 May (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Old-Fashioned Winters; William Sidney Mount, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Early American Arts and Crafts, 1954 February (Box 6, Folder 5)
    See also photographs in Series IX: Objects, folder Lighting Devices.
  - Tom Thumb; Lathrop C. Harper Spanish-American War Collection, 1954 March (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History of N-YHS; The Society's Treasures, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 150th Anniversary Hamilton-Burr Duel, 1954 July (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - IRT Subway 50th Anniversary, 1954 October (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Livingston Family; 300th Anniversary Spanish and Portuguese Synagogue; American Glass, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Includes contact sheets and related negatives from the synagogue exhibition.
  - Bicentennial of Fort Ticonderoga, 1955 April (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Arnold Shircliffe Menu Collection, 1955 October (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New York: The Empire State, 1956 February (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Eat, Drink, and Be Wary, 1956 May (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Presidential Campaign Cartoons, 1956 September (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - New York: City of Authors; Three New York City Architects; Mayors of New York, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Stuyvesant Family Portraits; Cartoons by C.D. Batchelor, 1958 April-May (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Includes a checklist of the objects from the Stuyvesant exhibition.
  - America in Daguerreotypes; American Feminine Costumes, 1958 October (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - America in Daguerreotypes. Oversize, 1958 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Rediscovered Painters of Upstate New York, 1959 February (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Hudson: River of History from Lake Champlain to the Sea, 1959 April (Box 7, Folder 5)
    In addition to photographic prints of objects, the folder includes negatives of photographs taken at the opening reception.
  - Niagara Falls: Artists Delight, Industry's Power; Presidential Campaign of 1860, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - It Paid to Advertise; A Nation Divided, 1861-1864; New York: Host to the World, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Silhouette Portraits; Passenger Transportation on Manhattan Island; Rare Books, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Audubon: Birds of America, 1963 October (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Colorful New Yorkiana; The New York Crystal Palace: America's First World's Fair, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Treasures of the New-York Historical Society, 1964 May (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - New York City Views, 1800-1900, 1965 April (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - American Military Weapons; Historic Hudson, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Glass Paperweights, 1966 April (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Merchants and Planters of the Upper Hudson Valley, 1700-1750, 1967 May (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Includes prints, contact sheets and negatives of the opening reception.
  - Theatrical Posters of Bygone Days; A Visit from St. Nick, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Includes contact sheet and related negatives for poster exhibition.
  - Circus Posters from the Days of the Big Top (2 folders), 1968 March (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
    Some of the photographs in this folder appear to be misfiled as they likely relate to a 1953 circus exhibition instead. On the other hand, the 1953 exhibition folder likely includes photographs from this 1968 exhibition. See the folder "Circus Time" above at April 1953.
  - Advertising Posters from the 19th Century, 1968 June (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - A Decade of Collecting, 1959-1969; Scrimshaw (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Glass Paperweights, 1970 February (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - A Visitor Looks at America: Baroness Hyde de Neuville, 1970 March (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - New York: Maritime City; Eye on the City: The Photographer in New York 1840-1900, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - City of Promise: Aspects of Jewish Life in New York, 1654-1970, 1971 March (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Includes negatives.
  - American Sculpture in Plaster, Wood, Metal, Stone; John Rogers: Household Gods, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Includes color slides of the Rogers exhibition.
  - Two Hundred Years of Toys in America; The American Revolution, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Road to the White House, 1972 July (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - John James Audubon: American Artist and Naturalist: Original Drawings for "Birds of America", 1972 October (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miniatures and Medals; New York Nostalgia, 1973 January (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Duyckincks: Merchants, Chiefs and Painters, 1973 October (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - River, Bowery, Mill, and Beaver: New York to 1765, 1973 October (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Old New York in Early Photographs, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Be My Valentine, 1974 February (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Manhattan Now: 14 Photographers Look at the Form of the City (5 folders), 1974 April (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
    Photographers: Robert Campbell, Adelaide de Menil, Sam Falk, Andreas Feininger, Mark Feldstein, Peter Fink, Evelyn Hofer, Edmund Gillon, Peter Kaplan, Sidney Kerner, Andre Kertesz, Martin Leifer, Dmitri Kessel, Peter Marks, and Rodman Rockefeller. Includes some negatives. Includes color slides of Kaplan's work.
  - Manhattan Now: 14 Photographers Look at the Form of the City (7 folders), 1974 April (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
  - Americans in Silhouette, 1974 May (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - New York, The New Empire: John Pintard and his Society (3 folders), 1974 October (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
    Also includes some contact sheets and negatives for multiple exhibitions; besides "Pintard," these include "City Views," "Ain't I a Woman," and "Shaker Objects."
  - The Sword of Rebellion is Drawn: New York in the Revolution; Ain't I a Woman?, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - America A La Carte: Bills of Fare of the 19th and 20th Century, 1975 July (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Shaker Objects from the Collection of Edward Derning and Faith Andrews (2 folders), 1975 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
    This folder and the next also include many Shaker-related photographs (a few with copy negatives) taken by William Winter.
  - John Trumbull: Patriot Artist of the Revolution; American Genre Paintings of the 19th Century, 1975 October (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Glass Paperweights (reinstallation); Mount Pleasant (Beekman House) Scale Miniatures, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The New York Cabinetmaker and His Use of Space (2 folders), 1976 January (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Words and Music: Sheet Music of Not So Long Ago; History at Home: Decorative Arts of the 18th and 19th Century, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Includes color slides of History at Home exhibition.
  - Campaigns, Conventions and Candidates; Operation-Sail '76 (Op-Sail), 1976 June (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Includes negatives of Op-Sail.
  - Selling New York: Advertising from the Landauer Collection; The Face of New York: Photographs of Andreas Feininger, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Dutch Republic in the Days of John Adams, 1775-1795, 1976 December (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Includes color transparencies.
  - Moving in the City: Three Centuries of Transportation (2 folders), 1976 December (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - Remember the Ladies: Women in America 1750-1815; Jenny Lind in New York; New York Then & Now, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - New York Stock Exchange; New York Fashions and Facades: Photographs by Bill Cunningham, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Think Small; Give Me That Old Time Religion, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Street Kids, 1978 February (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Art of the Conservator; Wish You Were Here; The American Magazine, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Over Here: World War I Posters, 1978 November (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - New York in the Forties: Photographs by Andreas Feininger, 1978 December (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Collecting for the Future: 25 Years of Acquisitions; Yesterday's View of the Future: Revisiting the World's Fair of 1939; Artists and Architects of the New York Subway, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Includes color slides for the Revisiting the World's Fair of 1939 exhibition, however it is not clear whether the slides relate to this 1979 exhibition or the 1989 exhibition of the same name. Includes negatives for the subway exhibition.
  - Knickerbocker Birthday; Murder! Murder Most Foul, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 55 Wall Street: A Working Landmark (Citibank Building); Tiffany Silver, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Includes contact sheets and related negatives for the silver exhibition.
  - That Belmont Look, 1980 January (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Includes contact sheets and negatives.
  - Panorama of Presidential Elections; A Remnant in the Wilderness: New York Dutch Scripture Paintings; Phrenology of the Land, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Drypoints of Mortimer Borne; New York Art on the Road; Small Folk: A Celebration of Childhood in America; The White Mountains: Place and Perception, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Includes negatives for Small Folks exhibition. See also the oversize folders for posters of the Small Folks and White Mountains exhibitions.
  - Society of Illustrators: 20 Years of Award Winners; Collaboration: Artists and Architects, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Of the Land's Bounty: Gardens Woods and Meadows; 200 Years of Freemasonry; The Mayor's House: Gracie Mansion and Other Dwellings, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Includes contact sheet and negatives for the Bounty exhibition.
  - Tales of Christmas Past; New York in Aerial Views, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - George Washington in New York State; Sailing Ships in Dutch Prints; FDR: A Centennial Celebration, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Manhattan Observed: 14 Photographers Look at New York, 1982 May (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Photographers represented in the folder include Jeff Perkell, Jan Staller, Ruth Orkin, Michael George, Harry Wilks, Serge Hambourg, Rhoda Galyn, and Leon Supraner. Includes negatives as well as prints. Includes subway-related color slides by Hambourg.
  - Grand Central Terminal; The Female Touch: The Ladies' Periodical as a Reflection of an Age, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Oom Pah Pah: The Great American Band (2 folders), 1982 July (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
    Includes contact sheets and related negatives, and other negatives.
  - A Collector's Sampler: Library Accessions 1980-1982; Greetings of the Year; Sampler of American Advertising From the Landauer Collection; [Indian Exhibition] (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Includes color slides from the Landauer exhibition.
  - A Heritage to Remember: The Black Experience in New York, 1983 January (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - A Celebration: American Landscape Painting, Genre Art & Drawing, 1983 February (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Includes color slides.
  - The Sage of Sunnyside: Washington Irving Bicentennial; A Child's World, 1983 March (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Includes color slides for Child's World.
  - The World of Tiffany: The Neustadt Collection of Tiffany Lamps, 1983 May (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - A Bridge Opens to Brooklyn; Artists' Views of Central Park; A Celebration of Opera, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Includes color slides of the Central Park exhibition.
  - Struggle for a Continent: Francis Parkman's "France and England in North America", 1983 October (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Includes color slides and a negative.
  - Firefighting on Parade, 1983 October (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - New York Themes: Paintings & Prints by William Meyerowitz and Theresa Bernstein; Lights, Camera, Action: New York's Silent Film Studios, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Includes color slides and negatives.
  - The Library of John Pintard: Book Collecting in the New Republic; Shanties to Skyscrapers: Robert L. Bracklow's Photographs of Early New York, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Includes color slides and negatives for the Bracklow exhibition.
  - New York and the China Trade (2 folders), 1984 February (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    This folder and the next includes negatives and color slides.
  - Sons of St. Patrick: Irish and Irish Organizations in New York; The Adirondacks: A Wilderness Preserved; Centennial Tribute to the Grolier Club, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Includes color slides for the Adirondacks exhibition.
  - Five New York Families; Treasures of Manuscript Americana, 1984 May (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Includes color slides of the Families exhibition.
  - Visions of Liberty, 1984 June (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lost in the Shuffle: Playing Cards and Board Games; Her Voice Was Heard: Women and Politics in America; Lurid Literature, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - A Pageant of Heraldry in Britain and America; Baroness Hyde de Neuville: Sketches of America, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Includes color slides and negatives for the heraldry exhibition.
  - Centuries of Childhood in New York; Karol Kozlowski, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    See also the oversize folders for an exhibition poster for Centuries of Childhood.
  - Audubon's Birds of North America: The Original Watercolors (2 folders), 1985 April (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
  - Chicago and New York: Architectural Interaction; Metropolis in Mourning: Ulysses S. Grant, 1822-1885, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - To the Publick: New York in Broadsides; Statue of Liberty Centennial Celebration, 1985 September (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Artist in Residence: North Country Art of Frederic Remington; The Great Fire of 1835: Sesquicentennial Anniversary, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Niagara: Two Centuries of Changing Attitudes, 1697-1901, 1986 January (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Prized Prints; P.T. Barnum, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - James Henry Cafferty, 1819-1869; Liberty's Legacy: New York's Ethnic Festivals; Storied Shores: Lake George in Legend and History, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Includes negatives for Liberty's Legacy exhibition.
  - Made for New York: Antique Toys from the Lawrence Scripps Wilkinson Collection, 1986 October (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - A Portrait of Livingston Manor, 1686-1850; Pleasure of Your Company: Parties and Balls in New York City, 1986 November (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Includes negatives of Livingston exhibition.
  - New York Bestiary: Pets and Pests of the Metropolis; Wagstaff Collection of American Silver, 1987 March (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Includes color slides of the bestiary exhibition.
  - The Hudson River and the Highlands: Photographs by Robert Glenn Ketchum, 1987 April (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Jackie Robinson: An American Journey, 1987 April (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Strong on Music: The New York Music Scene, 1836-1850, 1987 June (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution (2 folders), 1987 September (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Portraits of Power: Paintings from the Collection of the New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry; Ex Libris Rufus King, 1987 September (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Jasper Cropsey: Artist and Architect, 1987 October (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Blizzard of '88; Bellows, Bobbins, and Butter Churns: Keeping House in 19th Century America, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Francis William Edmonds: American Master in the Dutch Tradition; Artistic Houses: Lavish Interiors of 19th Century New York, 1988 April (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - The Rise and Fall of New York: Building and Unbuilding Manhattan; The Invisible Surface: Paper and the Printing Arts In Early America, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Includes negatives from the printing arts exhibition.
  - Arnold Newman: Five Decades, 1988 September (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hard Cider and Hot Air: The Selling of the President; Celebrating the Holidays in Old New York, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Putting New York on the Map; The Belknap Collection of Silver and Portraits, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Burr McIntosh: Polite Society, 1900-1910; Revisiting the World's Fair of 1939, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Includes negatives for the McIntosh exhibition. See also the 1979 folder above for an earlier Revisiting the World's Fair of 1939 exhibition; that folder includes color slides that possibly relate to this 1989 exhibition instead.
  - George Washington in New York, 1989 April (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Irving Browning: City of Contrasts, 1989 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Cased Images: The 150th Anniversary of Photography; An American Sampler: Folk Art from the Shelburne Museum, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Nicolino Calyo: 19th Century Views of New York; Below the Line: Living Poor in America, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Paris 1889: American Artists at the Universal Exposition, 1990 September (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Thomas Jefferson Bryan Gallery: Changing Attributions, 1990 September (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Charles Gilbert Hine: Impressions of a City, 1990 October (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Luman Reed Gallery Opening, 1990 November (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - ART what thou EAT: Images of Food in American Art, 1990 December (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Taste of Andrew Carnegie, 1991 May (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - New York Architecture: 1991 NYC/AIA Design Awards; McKim, Mead, & White's New York, 1991 June (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - New York in Watercolor: The Landscapes of William Rickarby Miller (1818-1893), 1991 September (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Includes a preliminary exhibition list.
  - Imagining the World: Columbian Iconography (2 folders), 1991 November (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - While They Fought: The Home Front in New York City, 1991 October (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Forever Wild: The Adirondack Experience; Louis XIV Chair Rediscovery, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Includes color contact sheets and related negatives for the Adirondacks exhibition. Includes color slides and negatives concerning the Louis XIV chair.
  - Egon Neustadt Collection of Tiffany Lamps, 1994 April (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Thomas Cole: Landscape into History; Treasury of the Past, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Elvis + Marilyn: 2 X Immortal, 1995 October (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Wrought from Common Clay: A Century of New York Stoneware; Unconventional Currier & Ives; Inventing the Skyline: The Architecture of Cass Gilbert, 1996 January, 1998 April, 2000 September (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Exhibition Installations, 1950s-1990s? (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Includes negatives of "Carlson putting in an exhibition with Joe Rapport"; color photo of gallery of Audubon works (1988?) and of gallery of George Washington-related objects (circa 1990?); and various other exhibition photos.
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. Brooklyn Museum (Egyptian and Assyrian Collection), circa 1940 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. Grolier Club (War of 1812); Chicago Historical Society (American Photography); New York Academy of Medicine (Beekman Collection), 1943?, 1954, circa 1960 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. Schools. Julia Richmond High School; When Old New York Was New; Other, 1939, 1950s? (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. Businesses. Oppenheim Collins; B. Altman; Union Dime Savings Bank; Franklin Society Federal Savings & Loan; Abraham and Strauss, 1945?, 1948, 1955, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. National Democratic Club (A Century and a Quarter of Democratic Political History), 1958 February (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. New York World's Fair (1 of 2), 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. New York World's Fair (2 of 2), 1964-1965 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 13)
    Includes oversize color transparencies and color prints of a Prentis Murply Period Room. See also Series XI. Negatives, folder Negative #43313-44577. Film, 5x7 for related color negatives.
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. PaineWebber Art Gallery (On with the Show! Circus and Theater Posters from the Collection of the New-York Historical Society), 1991 September (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. Equitable Gallery (19th Century Masterworks from the New-York Historical Society), 1994 June (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Exhibitions at Other Venues. Middlebury College of Art (European Paintings from the New-York Historical Society), 1996 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Oversize Exhibition Posters, 1940s? (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 3)
    Includes Knickerbocker Holiday (Peter Stuyvesant exhibition); Men and Ships of the American Navy; Washingtoniana and Lincolniana; Harry T. Peters Collection of Wood Engravings from American Weeklies, 1851-1900.
  - Oversize Exhibition Posters, 1972, 1976?, 1981, 1983, 1985 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 4)
    Includes Audubon and His World: The Birds of America (1972) (poster size background information sheet); Moving in the City: Three Centuries of Transportation in New York (1976?); The White Mountains: Place and Perceptions (1981); Small Folk: A Celebration of Childhood in America (1981) (2 versions); Twenty Years of Society of Illustrators Award Winners (1981); Firefighting on Parade, 1700-1865 (1983); Centuries of Childhood in New York: A Celebration on the Occasion of the 275th Anniversary of Trinity School (1985).
- Series III: School Programs, 1927-1990s?; 0.1 Linear feet
  The photographs in this series show various school groups taking tours, visiting exhibits, and watching plays and listening to lectures in the auditorium and the garden. Most of the photographs are unidentified and undated, but appear to be of grade school children, with some high school and college age students.
  - Groups at N-YHS, 1927-1990s? (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Groups from P.S. 44, Undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Public Programs, 1864, 1941-1990s; 1.62 Linear feet
  Arrangement Note
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  This series includes images related to programs held at N-YHS that were generally open to the public, such as concerts, lectures, theatrical works, film series, etc. (Programs limited to particular audiences are found in other series, especially the School Programs and Events & Publicity series.) Images include photographs of the program itself, a reception or related event, and stock publicity photographs of performers, though the specific content for any particular program varies. The series also includes copies of posters and signage for the 1864 public "Lectures on Egypt" sponsored by N-YHS.
  - Lectures on Egypt, 1864 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 1)
    Oversize poster (3 copies) for the lecture by Prof. Henry J. Anderson at Cooper Institute, the concluding lecture of a series, followed by an unrolling of the mummy. Signage (2 copies) for ticket sales.
  - Emma Thursby Memorial and Book Launch. Oversize, 1941 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    Includes one photograph of the principals at the event: Alexander Wall, author Richard Gipson, opera singer Jean Dickinson, and Walter Damrosch.